Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to create a level for our main menu.
If we go file, then go a new level and select basic.
Then go save and save this level inside of our level folder and just call this our main menu map.
Once you've done that, click on this little grid.
Then go open level blueprint and then pick and play of this level.
We're going to create and show our main menu widget.
If we drop off here and look for Create widget and put the widget, select the main menu that we just
made.
Then we're going to add this to our viewport.
Once you've done this, we can go compile, close this and let's test that.
Everything is working.
If I go play, we can see my 2D action platformer has the start quit and woops, it looks like I forgot
to hide this element.
I'm just going to quickly fix that.
I accidentally hit my text instead of hiding the button.
Okay, so I fixed it.
So if I go play, I should see my two D action platformer, the start and the clip on.
If I click start, it'll show me my level one.
If I click, go back, it will hide this element and then show me my main menu.
Okay, nice.
With this, we've created our main menu level, although there are a couple of things we need to fix
right now.
I can move around my main menu and this just kind of looks and feels a bit order to fix this.
We're going to create a whole game mode for our main menu.
If we go over to our Player Blueprint folder, just right click and Go Blueprint Class and select Game
mode and call this our main menu game mode.
If you remember earlier, we made this to DH game mode and our game mode needs a character that we're
going to start the game.
As for Main Menu.
We're just going to create a simple character, which is a camera.
So to do this, we just right click and go Blueprint class, select Pawn and just call this our camera
beep.
If we open it up.
Thank you.
To add and look for camera.
Think of compile and save.
And if we open up our main menu game mode.
Under the -- clause.
Select the camera.
Ben, go compile and see if we can close this.
And if we go to our well settings, let's just drag in our main menu game mode.
And I'm just going to go ad go basic and start, play, start.
Now, when I go play and I start my main menu game mode, I won't be able to move around because we're
playing the game as just that camera.
So I think my main menu level looks kind of boring, so we're going to add a background to it.
If we just close this and go over to level one.
Make sure to save everything before leaving.
And just copy this tarmac and this tarmac background.
Then we can delete this law and paste these backgrounds behind our character.
Position them so they look like they're in front of our camera.
And then just to add a little bit of a cool effect, we can go over to our very animation folder and
look for the idle flipbook.
I just find and grab it and just place this in front of our play store.
It may be a bit small, so let's just scale it up a bit and make sure to rotate it so it's facing our
player start.
Okay, so I found a nice place for my player character.
And if I go play, my main menu kind of looks like this and it's kind of nice, although I think it's
a bit bright.
So if we go to our camera blueprint.
That should make the brightness of this too.
So I look for brightness.
Check both these boxes and make this to.
Good play.
And I think that looks a bit better.
It's a bit more clear to see everything.
If you want to make it even more clear, because the buttons and the 2D action platformer text are a
bit hard to see.
If we go back to our main menu widget blueprint under palette.
Look for an image.
And the strikers in.
I make sure to anchor this image across the whole of the screen.
So select this one.
Then under each offset value, type in zero.
This will stretch the image across the whole of our screen.
Then under the order, make this minus one.
So it's behind everything.
Then if we go to appearance, make this black.
So I'm just going to go color and opacity and I'll make this black.
Then if you go to the Alpha Channel, just make this 0.1.
So the lower this value, the more transparent it's going to be.
This way we're adding a bit of like thickness to our main menu and I'll make a bit clearer to see the
text.
And now if I go compile and play.
We have to action and we can see stopped and quipped.
One more word of note.
If you want to change the color of the buttons, we can just select them and go back around color and
maybe I'll make this red.
And I'll just make this one red.
And that way it's a bit clearer to see.
So we can test our main menu.
I can go start then.
Also me level one.
If I click level one, it will take me to level one inside of my game.
Nice.
With this we have a working main menu.
There's just one more thing we need to do.
If I could play.
And currently we can see my mouse cursor.
How if I accidentally click my mouse cursor disappears and I can't click anywhere with my mouse again.
In order to fix this, if we go back to our main menu and go over to the graph.
And go to a bank construct.
A bank construct.
We want to right click and for get player controller.
And drag on here and look for set show, mouse cursor.
Just make sure this is checked and this will ensure that our mouse cursor stays on the screen.
Then drag off here and look for set input mode UI.
And just select this one set input mode UI only and convert this.
And here.
This will ensure that basically we are in UI mode when we're on our main menu.
Then we compile and close this and go over to our player blueprint.
We want to go to event construct.
And before we do anything, we want to right click and get player controller.
And drive up here and up for set input mode game only.
This will ensure that we start the game possessing our player character.
Just connect us into here.
And this into here.
And now, if I could compile and play, I can click anywhere with my mouse and I'm still up here.
If I could start then into level one, my mouse cursor will disappear and I'll start the game controlling
my player character.
With this, we have created our main menu.